<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Studio Plugins on Puget Audio</title>
    <link>https://puget.audio/plugins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Studio Plugins on Puget Audio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://puget.audio/plugins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Puget Passive EQ</title>
      <link>https://puget.audio/plugins/passive-eq/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puget.audio/plugins/passive-eq/</guid>
      <description>The Pultec is the textbook case for why WDF modeling matters. It&amp;rsquo;s a passive LC equalizer — literally inductors and capacitors in a ladder network — followed by a single 12AX7 tube makeup gain stage. This is the exact circuit topology Wave Digital Filters were invented to model with mathematical precision.&#xA;The boost-and-cut trick The famous &amp;ldquo;boost and cut at the same frequency&amp;rdquo; move? It&amp;rsquo;s not programmed. It&amp;rsquo;s not a DSP hack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puget Opto Compressor</title>
      <link>https://puget.audio/plugins/opto-compressor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puget.audio/plugins/opto-compressor/</guid>
      <description>Every major studio has a pair. The LA-2A is the most revered optical compressor ever built — two tube gain stages, a passive interstage network, and the T4B electro-optical attenuator that gives it that unmistakable program-dependent character.&#xA;The T4B: why it sounds like nothing else The T4B is a cadmium sulfide photoresistor driven by an electroluminescent panel. Its attack and release behavior is fundamentally nonlinear and program-dependent — loud transients hit harder and recover differently than sustained material.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puget FET Limiter</title>
      <link>https://puget.audio/plugins/fet-limiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puget.audio/plugins/fet-limiter/</guid>
      <description>The fastest compressor in the room. The 1176&amp;rsquo;s gain reduction element is a single JFET used as a voltage-variable resistor — which maps naturally to a nonlinear one-port in our WDF tree. The rest is discrete Class A transistor amplifier stages, transformer I/O, and the four ratio settings that change the feedback topology.&#xA;All Buttons In The &amp;ldquo;All Buttons In&amp;rdquo; mode — where all four ratio buttons are pressed simultaneously — isn&amp;rsquo;t a preset.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puget Variable-Mu</title>
      <link>https://puget.audio/plugins/variable-mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puget.audio/plugins/variable-mu/</guid>
      <description>The holy grail. Original 670s sell for $40,000+ when they surface. Twenty tubes, eleven transformers, and the 6386 remote-cutoff triode that makes variable-mu compression possible.&#xA;How variable-mu works The gain reduction happens by biasing push-pull tube stages — as the control voltage changes, the tube&amp;rsquo;s amplification factor (μ) changes with it. Smooth, musical, and harmonically complex in a way that VCA and FET designs can&amp;rsquo;t replicate.&#xA;We modeled the 6386 with a novel WDF triode model fitted to the original GE datasheet curves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puget Channel</title>
      <link>https://puget.audio/plugins/channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puget.audio/plugins/channel/</guid>
      <description>The most recognized preamp in recording history. The 1073 is all transformers and inductors — transformer-coupled Class A discrete preamp, inductor-based 3-band EQ with high-pass filter.&#xA;Every component that matters Every component that gives it that &amp;ldquo;Neve sound&amp;rdquo; — the Marinair transformers, the hand-wound inductors, the tantalum capacitors — is a WDF element in our model. Nothing is approximated. Nothing is left out.&#xA;Real inductors, not filter coefficients The inductor-based EQ is classic WDF territory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puget Studio Collection</title>
      <link>https://puget.audio/plugins/studio-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://puget.audio/plugins/studio-collection/</guid>
      <description>The five tools that built modern recording. Modeled from the circuit up. The Pultec shapes the tone. The 1176 catches the transients. The LA-2A levels the dynamics. The 670 glues the bus. The 1073 does everything in between.&#xA;An engineer can mix an entire record with these five tools. Generations of them have.&#xA;What&amp;rsquo;s included Plugin Models Type Puget Passive EQ Pultec EQP-1A Equalizer Puget Opto Compressor Teletronix LA-2A Compressor Puget FET Limiter UREI 1176LN Limiter Puget Variable-Mu Fairchild 670 Compressor/Limiter Puget Channel Neve 1073 Preamp/EQ $699 — Save $296 That&amp;rsquo;s roughly $140 per plugin vs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
